Ah!
But this is the sixth layer. If I go up, what about the curse?
It's okay, Riko.
I don't know exactly why this is, but the force field doesn't seem to exist here.
So you won't get hit with the curse.
Let's go on up. I want to learn more about these guys.
I can't read consciousnesses here since there's no force field regs, so I'm counting on you to stay vigilant.
Understood.
Nanuchi, are these guys...hellows?
Yeah, probably. But maybe they've retained their humanity somehow. They seem oddly intelligent.
And the body of that one, Maji Kaja. What the heck is it made of?
We need to know these types of things if we plan on going further. That's the sense I get.
The Sovereign of Dawn spoke of this. It was something about curses and blessings, right?
Who knows? But I hope this isn't the work of those white whistles.
Imiti, it is here.
Pruska!
What are you doing?!
Right, hold on!
Pruska...I think that... Pruska doesn't mind it.
Huh?
I think that Prushka doesn't mind it.
Why not?
Because the stone is not in its true form.
Medipo.
What was it in the common language?
It gives sound to a life's will?
Musical instrument?
Yes.
Upon becoming instruments, the stones get stronger and more precise.
To possess one without undergoing the process is not good for value.
Value?
Come with me.
Let Kaja show you to our Irohuru.
Hey, Maji Kaja was it?
Um, what in the world are you?
A holo, just like that nice-smelling, fluffy one with you.
Nah.
Sorry for being the one to have to say this, but I'm not so sure you're even a living creature.
Kaja's body is made of smells.
Kaja cannot speak in that form.
This body is a vessel.
Kaja wanted a body, not a vessel.
Kaja's body.
Wow, what is this place?
It's kind of like a market.
Yes, right you are.
A marketplace of value.
Things and not things can be bartered based on value.
Value?
I'm still not sure what that means.
Yeah, well, I bet it means something's true worth.
Is the currency like back home?
Doesn't seem like it.
Hey, look here!
These things used to belong to cave raiders!
This one's antiquated.
Must be from a long time ago.
I wonder when.
They all look to be in really good condition.
No way, isn't this...
Yeah, this is a section from Mother's letter!
Napu!
You must not touch that which has value without permission.
Machi-Cacha, I want that piece of paper!
You can obtain anything, as long as the value is in balance.
It's possible for us to barter for that?
Then which of my things can I trade for it?
Let me check what I've got in here.
You misunderstand.
You, yourself.
You would have a very good value.
For instance, your eyes, skin, or fat.
At the market, human children garner the most value.
Kaja also wants one if it is whole and intact.
Before you sell to someone else, I ask kindly that you speak to me first.
No, wait!
Not me!
I'm going all the way to the bottom of the netherworld!
A shame.
Kaja concedes.
Stealing value is the greatest of crimes.
Well, I can't just give up.
Can I buy it with my hair or nail clippings or something like that?
So did you two see the symbol marked on the money?
Yeah.
It's that same symbol.
Maybe Machi-Cacha doesn't actually know about that note then.
Why don't we try to get more info by acting like we're interested in everything here?
After all, the whole issue of who took Prushka seems to be forgotten.
That's a good one, Reg getting used to enemy territory.
Reg!
Nanachi!
Take a look over here!
They're so cute!
These hermit dwellers are for sale!
And they're even alive!
She's just being herself and enjoying this, huh?
Me!
Yeah!
So adorable!
Is this seller offering them as pets or are they for food?
Neither, actually.
But both.
Hmm.
This one, named Einbelitz, values small and adorable things crawling all over their body.
The excess animals have been displayed for bartering.
Kaja also trades as well, so as to make various vessels.
Sabasa over there values passing tubes throughout their own body.
Ah, and of course, Miss Keso values slicing apart the bodies of others.
So, yeah.
They sure do look the part now, don't they?
You see, the bodies of all hollows more or less take on the shape of our respective desires.
Every hollow here has challenged the netherworld, yet ended up with no place to go.
Thus, we chose to remain here.
When we offer our lives and turn into hollows, we become bound to this place and cannot leave.
But in exchange, we receive protection in a form in line with our desires.
You, nice smelling fluffy one.
Unlike us, you are a hollow from the old ritual site, are you not?
You possess true life.
You must have been protected by a very powerful desire.
It is of wonderful value.
So, uh, you're just like me.
You all dreamt of reaching the bottom of the abyss and settled on an adventure to explore it.
I can't stay here, but it's very nice to meet you all.
That's my friend, Mania, so play nice, okay?
Hey, that tickles.
Come on, stop it.
Quit!
Have a taste of your own medicine.
Mania!
No!
Don't take me at me!
Let me through!
Stop it!
Don't be so wrong with Mania!
Yeah!
Mania!
It's all that you-
Hey, move it!
Out of my way!
Yeah!
Give me Mania.
Well, what's with this?
The bones are so soft.
Whoa, hey now, stop moving around so much.
Mania!
Seems there wasn't anywhere for the air to go,
so the butt guts plopped out.
I'll push him back in.
But it's gonna be swollen for a while.
Ma, ma.
Kefu, what is its value?
No! Maybe it's not that kind of thing!
Is it so high you cannot determine it?
Yeah, that's right!
Kefe de Kefu.
Bevi mi hagu.
Ah, the balancing begins.
Ah!
Hello?
What is all that?
As you have witnessed, that one caused damage to a value exceeding their own.
It must be balanced.
Things they have saved, things they have hidden.
The balancing will not end until the values achieve equilibrium.
Nanachi, are you okay?
Don't worry. It's nothing, really.
It is the room. The village understands the desires of its inhabitants.
An undesired thing without buyers is transformed to a low value.
Things that are changed into value are lost forever.
Everyone here knows this, so we all abide by the protection.
Yeah, but what if I were to tell you doing that doesn't make me feel any better?
Is there a way you can make it stop?
Iruburu. The protection of the village is so strong Kaja can do nothing.
Or does it spell you so low there was actually no need for the balancing at all?
It's not that. I just, uh...
I just didn't want Mania to get hurt.
The shortfall is compensated with the body.
There are many buyers for bodies.
For there are some who value knowing what's inside.
Well, if stealing value is such a crime here, then how do you justify what happened with Prushka?
That stone was brought from outside of Iruburu.
Things that happen outside are not protected by the power of the village.
So then, you're saying you aren't the ones who stole her?
Hottie me.
What the?
Oh God, what's this?
That is yours.
It has finally reached the amount of your damaged value.
What?
But do I really have to accept this?
Mayim, even if you were thrown away, it would not be discarded.
The value is bound to you.
Hanlisuku Hadi.
How do I put it?
You will not want for human food or a place to sleep.
Kaja must take leave now.
Farewell.
Huh? Hold on!
After what has happened, everyone now knows your value.
Kaja believes no one will harm you.
Hey, um, we're looking for some lodging for the night.
Do you know of any place where we could stay?
Uh, I'm not really sure how this is going to work.
Hanlisuku?
Huh?
Mojimamodi.
Uh, Hanlisuku.
Hanlisuku.
There's poop down there, Riko!
What the?
Huh?
Kondos.
Maybe.
Oh, whoa!
They understood that?
Riko, how do you know to say that?
Earlier, Maji Kaja said that word when talking about eating food in a place to sleep.
Hanlisuku, right?
Oh.
You're pretty amazing.
The language is difficult to decipher.
At times like this, even if you don't know any of the native language,
it's key to keep calm and make yourself understood.
Also, when I lived up top, our orphanage held guided tours.
But I admit I wasn't really all that good at it, though.
We witnessed something awful, but you know, maybe more than anyone, Riko understands we
can't afford to let ourselves get down at a time like this.
Mm-hmm.
Most likely, she just can't contain her excitement.
Pardon, I'd like to rent a room for four of us, please.
It would be me, Nanachi, Reg, and Mania.
Do-do-do-do-do-do-do.
I don't know how much it is.
Nemo.
And some food as well.
I don't want to spend all of this.
Makes me feel bad.
But we kind of have to.
After all, we need a safe place to treat Mania's injuries.
So this is her room.
This is the toilet.
This is food.
Oh, wow.
That's crazy.
It's not half bad.
Yeah, you're right.
Hey, given the color of this, and all the insects swarming in and around it, you sure
it's okay?
It tastes fine.
Stuff that's horrible, like Nanachi's cooking, is honestly pretty rare.
Besides, I bet we won't be able to eat this anywhere else.
I don't want to miss my chance and regret it.
This journey is a once-in-a-lifetime thing.
Mm-hmm.
I told you so.
Need something to warm up your tummy?
I'm okay.
With this sort of thing, it's better to get diarrhea sooner than tired.
Huh?
Oh, oh.
Bathroom!
This is something I've seen countless times at the orphanage.
She'll probably spend half the day glued to the toilet.
What do you want to do today?
I think I'll probably go look for things to help out Mania and Riko.
You want to come with me?
What's up?
Where are all the hollows going?
An earthquake.
No, it was more like an impact.
Majikaja!
What's going on?
What's that sound?
Hadi.
It must be Fapta.
Kaja must see.
Fapta?
Very rare.
Always very angry.
Fapta is the embodiment of value.
Can go anywhere.
Will never perish.
But usually stays away.
Kaja wants to see.
Did you hear that, Reg?
Yeah.
Fapta can go anywhere, but is rarely seen.
It's probably the one who left us that nasty note, huh?
Let's go, Nanichi.
Wait, hold on.
Leaving a sick Riko and an injured Mania behind makes me uneasy.
Can I ask you to do some recon?
Yeah, roger that.
If anything comes up, I'll call on the comm device.
Don't let your guard down.
And turn back if you aren't sure what to do.
Got it.
What happened to the human child?
She's dealing with a painful, upset stomach.
Hadiva, that is not good.
Kaja does not want the value of the human child to fall.
Do you know where they sell clean water and fruit I can bring back to Riko for her stomach?
Kaja will guide you.
Hadiva, though Kaja wants to see Fapta, but Kaja...
Which one will it be?
Well, about this Fapta, what exactly are we talking about?
Hadiva, yes.
The meaning of Fapta in the common language is...
How do you say it?
A high status female.
Oh, yeah?
She a princess or something?
Yes, correct.
A princess.
Princess of the hollows.
What?
Are they asking us something?
We are Ganja.
A group of explorers in search of the hidden Golden City.
It's listening.
They're sussing out our intentions based on reactions.
And likely our speech patterns.
This is great.
I love it.
I feel their intelligence.
Ganji.
You think they want us to follow them?
Everyone, stay on your guard.
Oh, my gosh.
The Golden City.
We're really here.
Oh, my gosh.
The Golden City.
We're really here.
We had finally arrived.
But after our long, arduous adventure,
we had still been unable
to find a way to survive.
Thank you.